Guide to the Frank Whitson Fetter Papers, 1902-1992
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Professional Files, 1925-1990. (Box 51)
  - Alphabetical Files (Box 51)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1959 (Box 51)
    - American Economic Association: (Box 51)
      - National Register of Scientific and Technical Personnel, 1951-1964 (Box 51)
      - Nominating Committee, 1963 (Box 51)
    - Broyles, Bill: (Box 51)
      - Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 51)
      - General, undated, (2 folders) (Box 51)
      - Loyalty oaths, undated (Box 51)
      - Vote, undated (Box 51)
    - Catalogs: Publications, 1960s (Box 51)
    - Catalogs: Publications (Box 52)
      - 1970s-1980s, (2 folders) (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d (Box 52)
    - Committee on International Exchange of Persons: Conference: Board of Associated Research Councils, 1963-1966 (Box 52)
  - Conferences and Seminars (Box 52)
    - Budapest, 1982 (Box 52)
    - Economic History Society, 1986 (Box 52)
    - History of Economics Society, 1986 (Box 52)
    - International Congress: Copenhagen, 1974 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous, 1933-1990, undated, (10 folders) (Box 52)
    - Quad-City Council, 1953 (Box 52)
    - Wealth of Nations, 1976 (Box 52)
  - Fellowships and Grants (Box 52)
    - American Philosophical Society: (Box 52)
      - Grant correspondence and application information, 1954-1985, (3 folders) (Box 52)
      - Printed material, 1985 (Box 52)
    - The Ford Foundation Fellowship: Correspondence, application information and miscellaneous, 1960-1962, (2 folders) (Box 52)
    - The Ford Foundation Research Grant: Application, 1957 (Box 52)
    - Fullbright Research Grant, 1954 (Box 52)
    - Guggenheim Fellowship: (Box 52)
      - Applications, 1937 (Box 52)
      - Clippings, 1937 (Box 52)
      - Correspondence, 1935-1937 (Box 52)
      - Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Box 52)
      - Miscellaneous, 1941-1947 (Box 52)
    - Guggenheim Foundation: (Box 53)
      - Printed material, 1925-1989 (3 vols.) (Box 53)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities: Correspondence and miscellaneous, 1970-1982 (Box 53)
    - Northwestern University Research Grant: Applications, 1925-1967, (3 folders) (Box 53)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Bellagio Center): Correspondence and application information, 1973-1983, (2 folders) (Box 53)
    - Social Science Research Council Grant: Applications, correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1969-1971 (Box 53)
    - Harvard: (Box 53)
      - Center for International Affairs, undated (Box 53)
      - Development Advisory Service, 1965 (Box 53)
      - Kress Library of Business and Economics: (Box 53)
        - Annual reports, 1950-1984 (Box 53)
        - Fellowship Fund, undated (Box 53)
      - Library, undated (Box 53)
    - History of Economics Society, undated (Box 53)
    - History of Political Economy, 1968-1987, (3 folders) (Box 53)
  - Lectures and Speeches (Box 53)
    - Can Federal Reserve Policy Stimulate Economic Recovery Without Jeopardizing Our International Gold Reserve? (Chicago, Ill.), 1961 (Box 53)
    - Can We Check Inflation By Taxation? (Swarthmore), 1942 (Box 53)
    - Dartmouth Land That Went to Princeton: Aftermath of Dartmouth College Case (Hanover, N.H.), 1969 (Box 53)
    - A Dilemma For Economics (University of Chicago), 1946 (Box 53)
    - Does America Breed Depression? (London), 1955 (Box 53)
    - Does Inflation Stimulate Exports? (Radio [WRNY], New York), 1933 (Box 53)
    - Economics and the Quest for Social Justice (New York yearly meeting [Religious Society of Friends]), 1936 (Box 53)
    - Economist in Parliament, 1780-1868 (Manchester, England), 1971 (Box 53)
    - Economists' Role in Early 19th Century English Controversies (Indianapolis, Ind.), 1956 (Box 53)
    - Foreign Capital and American Economic Development (St. Louis, Mo.), 1963 (Box 53)
    - Foreign Investment and the American Economy (Ill.), 1946 (Box 53)
    - Gold Standard and the Depression (Stevens Institute), 1933 (Box 53)
    - How Important Has Foreign Capital Been in Economic Development? (Amherst, Mass.), 1967 (Box 53)
    - Influence of Economists in Parliament on British Legislation from Ricardo to John Stuart Mill (Copenhagen, Denmark), 1974 (Box 53)
    - Inter-Country Comparison to the Role of Foreign Capital in Economic Development Before 1914 (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1968 (Box 53)
    - International Trade and World Peace (Haverford), 1939 (Box 53)
    - Joint Committee Economics Report Testimony (Washington, DC), 1955 (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous talks, 1928-1939, (10 folders) (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous talks, 1940-1981, (31 folders) (Box 54)
    - Problems of Currency and foreign Exchange in South America (New York, N.Y.), 1933 (Box 54)
    - Recent History of European Currencies (Johnsonburg, N.J.), 1933 (Box 54)
    - Reconstruction and Development (New York), 1946 (Box 54)
    - Relation of the History of Economic Thought to Economic History (Chicago, Ill.), 1964 (Box 54)
    - Remarks Made at Services for R.C. Brooks (Swarthmore, Pa.), 1941 (Box 54)
    - Remarks on Academic Freedom (Northwestern University), 1953 (Box 54)
    - Report of Meeting of International Economic History Association (Copenhagen), 1974 (Box 54)
    - Some Problems of Excessive Armament Expenditures (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1940 (Box 54)
    - Symposiums: (Box 54)
      - History of Economic Thought (Duke University), 1968 (Box 54)
      - International Economics (Concord, N.H.), 1968 (Box 54)
    - What's This trade Issue All About? (Chicago, Ill.), 1953 (Box 54)
    - World Economic Problems (New York City, N.Y.), 1933 (Box 54)
    - Midwest Economic Association, 1941-1990, (3 folders) (Box 54)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1946-1990, undated, (7 folders) (Box 54)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research: (Box 55)
      - 1966-1991 (Box 55)
      - Math: Economic course notes (Box 55)
    - People: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 55)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1936-1937 (Box 55)
    - St. Louis Post Dispatch Editorials, 1930-1934, undated, (4 folders) (Box 55)
  - Teaching (Box 55)
    - Dartmouth College: (Box 55)
      - Acceptance correspondence applications, 1966-12967 (Box 55)
      - Miscellaneous, 1968-1990 (Box 55)
      - Denison University: Visiting examiner: Correspondence, exams, 1953 (Box 55)
    - Haverford College: (Box 55)
      - Grade books, 1934-1948, (2 folders) (Box 55)
      - Faculty Committee report, 1940 (Box 55)
      - Humanistic studies and readings on Japan, ca. 1942 (Box 55)
      - Institute of International Relations: (Box 55)
        - Correspondence, 1935, Jan.-June (Box 55)
        - Notes, reports/speeches, correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 55)
        - Programs, schedules, notes, 1935 (Box 55)
      - International Trade and Finance (Ec 46) syllabus, 1946-1947 (Box 55)
      - Latin American Economic Problems (Ec 146): (Box 55)
        - Assignments, exams, notes, syllabi, 1941-1947 (Box 55)
        - Bibliographies, undated (Box 55)
        - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 55)
      - Memorandum to faculty, 1942 (Box 55)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 55)
      - Money and Banking (Ec 3a, Ec 4a) assignments, syllabi, exams, report topics, articles, notes, 1940-1948, (3 folders) (Box 55)
      - National Income and Investment (Ec 13a) syllabi, 1946-1948 (Box 55)
      - Newspaper, 1939, Nov. 21 (Box 55)
      - Notes, undated (Ec 5-5b) (Box 55)
      - Readings in Foreign Economics (Ec 17a) assignments, syllabi, grades, notes, correspondence, 1942-1947 (Box 55)
      - Transportation (Ec 7b) assignments, syllabi, reports, miscellaneous, correspondence, 1934-1940 (Box 55)
    - Northwestern University: State Department Seminar correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 55)
    - Princeton University: (Box 55)
      - Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (Ec 115) notes, references, 1928-1928 (Box 55)
      - Foreign/International Trade and Commercial Policy (Ec 303) assignments, syllabi, exams, lectures, notes, 1926-1928 (Box 55)
      - International Economic Policies (Ec 526) assignments, syllabi, notes, 1934 (Box 55)
      - International Finance (Ec 402) assignments, syllabi, lectures, notes, 1928-1930 (Box 55)
      - International Trade (Ec 525) notes, bibliographies, 1932-1933 (Box 55)
      - International Trade Theory (Ec) assignments, syllabi, notes, 1930-1934 (Box 55)
      - Money (Ec 507-508) assignments, notes, 1931-1932 (Box 55)
      - Money and Banking (Ec 401) assignments, lectures, syllabi, exams, notes, 1928-1934, (4 folders) (Box 55)
    - Princeton University: (Box 56)
      - Transportation (Ec 408) lectures, notes, 1925 (Box 56)
    - School of Advanced International Studies: (Box 56)
      - Conference announcement, 1947 (Box 56)
      - International Economic Relations commencement program, notes, students, syllabus, 1945-1946 (Box 56)
      - International Investment and Development: (Box 56)
        - Assignments, commencement program, exam, readings, students, syllabus, 1945-1946 (Box 56)
        - Student papers, 1947 (Box 56)
    - Swarthmore College: (Box 56)
      - American Economic History; Finance (Ec ) exams, 1933-1934 (Box 56)
      - Contemporary Economic Problems Comprehensive Exams (Ec): Exams, 1931-1933 (Box 56)
      - Economic Theory (Ec) exams, 1932-1940 (Box 56)
      - Government Business (Ec) exams, 1934-1936 (Box 56)
      - International Economics (Ec) exams, 1934-1940 (Box 56)
      - Money and Banking; Social Economics (Ec) exams, 1935-1940 (Box 56)
      - Public Control of Business; Private and Public Finance (Ec) exams, 1937-1940 (Box 56)
    - University of Illinois, Circle Campus: Memorandum of Understanding, 1967 (Box 56)
    - University of Wisconsin: Seminar In International Economics (Ec 253) Viner papers, undated (Box 56)
- Pictures, 1909-1988, undated (bulk 1930). (Box 56)
  Contains black and white (a few color) photographs, and negatives of Fetter, family members, friends, and colleagues. Chiefly pictures taken during a trip to Russia in 1930, when Fetter visited Kasan and Moscow, and other travels around the world. Contains one album composed of pictures relating to the Import/Export Bank of Ecuador. Arranged alphabetically by subject (usually a geographic location), followed by people, places, and trips categories.
  Photographs from Russia (1930) have been digitized and are available in Americans in the Land of Lenin - Duke Digital Collections
  - Negatives: Unidentified people, 1912, undated (Box 56)
  - Photographs: (Box 56)
    - Chile, 1923-1927 (Box 56)
    - China, 1929 (Box 56)
    - Colorado: Skiing trip, 1976 (Box 56)
    - Cuba: Commission Cuban Affairs, undated (Box 56)
    - Economic History meetings, 1955, 1968 (Box 56)
    - Ecuador: (Box 56)
      - Export-Import Bank/Central Bank of Ecuador, photo album, ca. 1940 (Box 56)
      - Export/Import Bank Commission. 1939 (Box 56)
    - Estonia, 1928 (Box 56)
    - Frank Fetter and family, ca. 1909-1988, undated (Box 56)
    - Germany, 1930 (Box 56)
    - Kemmerer Commission: (Box 56)
      - undated (Box 56)
      - Chile, 1925; Poland, 1926; Ecuador, 1927 (Box 56)
    - Latvia, 1928 (Box 56)
    - Lend-Lease Administration: India, 1943-1944 (Box 56)
    - People: (Box 56)
      - Identified, 1914-1960, undated (Box 56)
      - Unidentified, 1923-1929, undated (Box 56)
    - Places: (Box 56)
      - Identified, 1950-1968 (Box 56)
      - Unidentified, 1930-1988, undated (Box 56)
    - Poland and Latvia, 1928 (Box 56)
    - Princeton University, 1926 (Box 56)
    - Russia: (Box 56)
      - Picture log, 1930 (Box 56)
      - 1930, (2 folders) (Box 56)
      - Dom Odexa, 1930 (Box 56)
      - Kasan and Moscow, 1930 (Box 56)
      - Kolxoza, 1930 (Box 56)
      - S.S. Homeric, 1930 (Box 56)
      - Volga, 1930 (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous: Contact prints, 1930 (Box 56)
    - South America, 1922 (Box 56)
    - Switzerland (Vienna) Economic History meeting, 1965 (Box 56)
    - Trips: (Box 56)
      - Canoe,1931-1934, (2 folders) (Box 56)
      - Hiking, 1934, Jan. (Box 56)
- Oversize Materials (Box 56)
  Of particular interest are the 1925-1927 Kemmerer Commission Scrapbook, and the 1929 four-volume report of the Kemmerer China Commission of Financial Experts. There are also research materials, newspaper clippings, and various statistical sheets.
  - Personal Files Series (Box 56)
    - Travel (Box 56)
      - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 57)
    - Alphabetical Files (Box 57)
      - Certificates, Misc., undated (Box 57)
      - Ozone Club, 1935 (Box 57)
  - Professional Files Series (Box 57)
    - Teaching (Box 57)
      - (Haverford College) Newspaper, 1939, Nov. 21 (Box 57)
  - Commission, Consulting and Government Service Series (Box 57)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 57)
    - Northwestern University, 1953-1964, n.d (Box 57)
  - Publications Series (Box 57)
    - Published Books (Box 57)
      - Articles of interest, 1965; Development of British Monetary Orthodoxy: Research: British Banking, undated (Box 57)
    - Unpublished Books and Manuscripts (Box 57)
      - Foreign Capital in Economic Development: Research: (Box 57)
        - Denmark: Statistics: (Box 57)
          - undated (Box 57)
          - 1st Den Run, 1967 (Box 57)
        - Japan: Misc., undated; Statistics, 1968-1970 (Box 57)
        - Sweden: Statistics: (Box 57)
          - 1967-1970 (Box 57)
          - 1st Sweden Run, 1967-1970 (Box 57)
        - Canada: Statistics, undated (Box 57)
        - Australia: Statistics, 1968-1970, undated; Butlin-Kuznets, 1960; Statistics: First Australian Run, 1967 (Box 57)
        - Italy: (Box 57)
          - Misc., undated (Box 57)
          - Statistics: (Box 57)
            - undated (Box 57)
            - 1st Italy Run, 1967 (Box 57)
            - 3rd Italy Run, 1967 (Box 57)
            - 1967-1970 (Box 57)
    - Published Books (Box 57)
      - Restricted (Box 57)
        - Economist in Parliament, (6 folders) (Box 58)
          - Research: (Box 58)
            - Thompson, Thomas Perronet, 1830-1866, undated (Box 58)
            - Brougham (Brougham & Vaux), 1832-1854, undated (Box 58)
            - Grey (Howick), 1810-1834, undated (Box 58)
            - Parnell, Sir Henry, 1808-1836 (Box 58)
            - Herris, undated (Box 58)
            - Electoral Facts, 1818-1865 (Box 58)
            - Miscellaneous election notes, 1760-1830 (Box 58)
            - Miscellaneous research, 1828-1843 (Box 58)
          - Name of Economists in Parliament: (Box 58)
            - Wilmont (Horton), Sir Robert John, 1823-1834 (Box 58)
            - Huskisson, William, 1814-1842, undated (Box 58)
            - Lewis, Sir George Corwall, 1942-1953 (Box 58)
            - Hume, Joseph, 1935, undated (Box 58)
            - Thorton, Henry, 1802(?) and 1971, undated (Box 58)
            - Horner, Francis, 1816 (Box 58)
        - Development of British Monetary Orthodoxy: Research: (Box 59)
          - Attwood, Thomas, 1816-1840, undated (Box 59)
          - Parliamentary votes, 1808-1833 (Box 59)
          - Miscellaneous research, 1810-1842, undated (Box 59)
        - The Irish Pound: Reviews, reprints, publishing, 1954 (Box 59)
        - Selected Economic Writings of Thomas Attwood: Misc. research, 1830-1843 (Box 59)
        - The Transfer Problem: Formal Elegance or Historical Realism: Notes and research, 1968 (Box 59)
        - Monetary and Financial Policy in 19th Century Britain: Research: Miscellaneous research, 1969 (Box 59)
    - Unpublished Books and Manuscripts (Box 59)
      - Overend, Gurney, (4 folders): (Box 60)
        - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 60)
        - Research: (Box 60)
          - Barclay's Bank, 1837-1866 (Box 60)
          - Baring Brothers Bank, 1839-1866 (Box 60)
          - Books and Articles, 1860-1867, undated (Box 60)
          - British Museum and Library, 1866 (Box 60)
          - British Theses, 1869 (Box 60)
          - Rothchild, 1838-1864 (Box 60)
          - Glyn, 1866 (Box 60)
          - Law cases, 1865-1874 (Box 60)
          - Incorporation papers, 1865-1893 (Box 60)
          - Liquidator's report, 1866-1893 (Box 60)
          - Wills and death notices, 1906-1932 (Box 60)
          - Miscellaneous testimony, 1869 (Box 60)
  - General Research Files Series (Box 60)
    - Published Articles and Pamphlets (Box 60)
      - The Politics of the Bullion Report: Jasper Atkinson: Research and letters, undated (Box 62)
      - The Economists' Tariff Protest of 1930 (Box 62)
      - "The Authorship of Economic Articles in the Edinburgh Review, 1802-1847": Research, 1953 (Box 62)
      - Robert Torrens: Colonel of Marines and Political Economist: Research and letters, undated (Box 62)
      - Lenin Keynes and Inflation: Research and clippings, 1922-1978 (Box 62)
      - Some Pitfalls in the Use of Bank of England Statistics: Research, 1967 (Box 62)
      - Hudson Bay Blankets: Reflections on a minor tariff issue: Research and notes (Box 62)
    - Alphabetical Files (Box 62)
      - British history, 1971 (Box 62)
      - Committee on Bank Acts: App 41: Scotch Opinion, 1858, undated (Box 62)
      - Declaration of Independence, 1943, undated (Box 62)
      - Gold and silver ration, undated (Box 62)
      - Rice, Thomas Spring, 1970 (Box 62)
      - Thornton family: Various letters, 1814-1820 (Box 62)
    - Unpublished Articles and Pamphlets (Box 62)
      - Foreign Capital in Economic Development: Research: (Box 62)
        - United States (Box 62)
          - Misc., undated (Box 62)
          - Statistics: (Box 62)
            - 1967-1970 (Box 62)
            - 1st USA Run, 1967 (Box 62)
            - 2nd USA Run, 1967 (Box 62)
        - Norway: (Box 62)
          - Misc., 1970, undated (Box 62)
          - Statistics: (Box 62)
            - 1966-1968 (Box 62)
            - 1st Norway Run, 1967 (Box 62)
        - Charts and tables, 1970, undated (Box 62)
  - CORRESPONDENCE SERIES, 1970-1976 (Box 63)
  - Commissions, Consulting and Government Service Series (Box 63)
    - Kemmerer Commission: (Box 63)
      - Bolivia, 1922 (Box 63)
      - Chile, 1900-1925; notes and research, undated, (2 folders) (Box 63)
      - China: (Box 63)
        - Maps, 1929 (Box 63)
        - Miscellaneous, ca. 1929 (Box 63)
    - Export/Import Bank: (Box 63)
      - Ecuador: (Box 63)
        - Notes, miscellaneous, undated (Box 63)
        - Maps, 1938, June (Box 63)
    - American Hemisphere Office: Ecuador: Map, 1937 (Box 63)
    - Northwestern University, 1960, undated (Box 63)
  - Publications Series (Box 63)
    - Published Books (Box 63)
      - Economists in Parliament: Research: Currency: Bank of England, 1832 (Box 63)
    - Unpublished Books and Manuscripts (Box 63)
      - Overend Gurney: (Box 63)
        - Research: (Box 63)
          - Clippings, 1866-1869 (Box 63)
          - Parliamentary debates, 1869 (Box 63)
          - Gurney genealogy, undated (Box 63)
          - Miscellaneous, 1866-1867 and 19956, undated (Box 63)
          - Miscellaneous newspaper clippings and notes, 1847-1869 (Box 63)
      - Newsprint Oversize: (Box 62)
        - General correspondence, 1937-1980 (Box 62)
        - Commissions, Consulting, and Government Service, 1926-1940 (Box 62)
      - Newsprint Oversize: (Box 62)
        - Northwestern University, 1958-1964, undated (Box 62)
        - Publications, 1928-1984 (Box 62)
        - General Research, 1933-1976 (Box 62)
        - Personnel, 1955 (Box 62)
  - General Research Series (Box 62)
    - Alphabetical Files (Box 62)
      - Assassination at Sarajevo, 1914, undated (Box 62)
      - Newspapers 1-13, 1973, undated, (3 folders) (Box 62)
    - Published Articles and Pamphlets (Box 62)
      - Witch Hunt in the Lincoln County (Box 62)
      - Research and clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 62)
  - Personal Files Series (Box 62)
    - Alphabetical Files (Box 62)
      - Swarthmore (Box 62)
      - Personal files, financial papers (Box 62)
      - Real estate: 5800 Orchard Lane, Winnetta, Ill. (Box 62)
      - Correspondence, miscellaneous, 1948-1967 (Box 62)
      - Professional Files: Alphabetical files: Midwest Economic Association (Box 62)
      - Pictures: (Box 62)
        - Kemmerer Commission, undated (Box 62)
        - Princeton University, 1926 (Box 62)
  - Commissions, Consulting and Government Service Series (Box 62)
    - Kemmerer Commission: (Box 62)
      - Ecuador, printed material, 1926 (Box 62)
      - China, miscellaneous, 1929-1930 (Box 62)
    - Personal Files: Alphabetical Files: Hanover Water Co., 1971-1984, undated (Box 62)
  - RESTRICTED MATERIAL - Box closed. (Box 61)